Guide to the Barry Gifford Papers M0927
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Barry Gifford papers
circa 1967 - 2012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gifford, Barry, 1946-
M0927
57 Linear Feet: 57 boxes; 1 map folder
Scope and Contents
The Barry Gifford Papers comprise more than forty-eight boxes of archival material, the vast majority of which related to the publication process of Gifford's many books. The largest subseries is composed of manuscript material, including correspondence with publishers and editors, typewritten and handwritten drafts of books, and research materials. As well, there are fifteen boxes of Gifford's notebooks, which contain partial drafts of books as well as individual poems, journal entries, and memoranda. There is also a significant file of correspondence, notable primarily for the six boxes of letters Gifford wrote to his longtime friend and associate, bookseller Marshall Clements. Finally, the collection contains copies of books and other published material used in his research.
Biographical / Historical
Poet, biographer, novelist, memoirist, and essayist, Barry Gifford was born October 18, 1946 in Chicago to Adolph, a pharmacist, and Dorothy Colby Gifford, a model. He was raised in Chicago and in Key West and Tampa, Florida. Gifford attended the University of Missouri where he played baseball. After leaving college, Gifford served in the Air Force Reserves, and worked variously as a merchant seaman, musician, journalist, editor, and truck driver.
Gifford, a prolific writer, has penned more than thirty books in a number of genres. His works include poetry, short fiction, novels, essays, biographies, memoir, and dramatic plays. Critics have acclaimed his work as colorful, quirky, and unique. Reviewer Jay Tolson (Los Angeles Times Book Review) praised Gifford for avoiding "facile or fashionable explanations [of the mystery of life]."
Others have noted Gifford's frequent explorations of the boundaries of traditional literary genres, as when he blended memoir and fiction in a biography of his father. He also co-authored an unconventional "oral" biography of writer Jack Kerouac, basing the account almost entirely on interviews with Kerouac's friends and acquaintances. In the Saturday Review, Bruce Cook called the book "first rate" and admired its portrayal of "a sense of Kerouac the man." Gifford's study of Beat personalities continued with a volume of letters he edited called As Ever: The Collected Correspondence of Allen Ginsberg and Neal Cassady.
Gifford's ability to evoke characters and moods in different regions of the country stems from his longtime fascination with language, one he traces back to his early years listening to his father's gangster friends in Chicago. Some of his work also reveals the impact of his self-identified literary influences: Jack London, Jack Kerouac, B. Traven, Ezra Pound, Emily Dickinson, Jean Rhys, Marcel Proust, and Gustave Flaubert.
In the late 1980s, Gifford's fourth novel caught the eye of director David Lynch, who adapted it into the screenplay and motion picture of the same name. Wild at Heart won the Palme d'Or, the highest honor, at the Cannes Film Festival in 1990. The success of this film spurred the popularity of Gifford's novels. Gifford subsequently wrote increasingly surreal fiction about the characters from Wild at Heart. He has also collaborated with Lynch on several other projects, most recently on the screenplay Lost Highway and teleplays for HBO about a mysterious hotel in New Orleans.
All told, Gifford has published more than thirty volumes. Among his many projects, T he Devil Thumbs a Ride and other Unforgettable Films, is a collection of essays on film noir. He has also written 11 volumes of poetry, several short stories and novellas, a biography (with Lawrence Lee) of William Saroyan, and ten novels. They are Landscape with Traveler, Port Tropique, An Unfortunate Woman, Wild at Heart, 59° and Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango, A Good Man to Know, Arise and Walk, Baby Cat-Face, Perdita Durango, and, most recently, The Sinaloa Story.
Gifford has been the recipient of the Maxwell Perkins Award from PEN, a Fellowship in Creative Writing for Fiction from the National Endowment for the Arts, the Art Directors Club of New York Merit Award, and a PEN Syndicate Fiction prize.
Gifford lives with his wife, Mary Lou Nelson, and two children in Berkeley, California.
Chronology
1967 The Blood of the Parade [poetry]
Awarded Silverthorne Press Award for Poetry, (for The Blood of the Parade)
1973 Coyote Tantras [poetry] A Boy's Novel [short stories / novellas]
Kerouac's Town, photographs by Marshall Clements [essays]
1974 Visiting Lecturer, SUNY Buffalo
1976 Persimmons: Poems for Paintings [poetry]
The Boy You Have Always Loved [poetry]
Selected Poems of Francis Jammes [translation]
1977 A Quinzaine in Return for a Portrait of Mary Sun [poetry]
As Ever: The Collected Correspondence of Allen Ginsberg and Neal Cassady [editor]
1978 Lives of the French Impressionist Painters [poetry]
Jack's Book: An Oral Biography of Jack Kerouac, with Lawrence Lee [biography].
Receives American Library Association Notable Book Award (for Jack's Book)
1979 Horse Hauling Timber out of Hokkaido Forest [poetry]
1980 Landscape With Traveler: The Pillow Book of Francis Reeves [novel]
Port Tropique [novel]
1981 Beautiful Phantoms: Selected Poems 1968-1980
The Neighborhood of Baseball: A Personal History of the Chicago Cubs [memoir/nonfiction]
1982 Francis Goes to the Seashore [short stories / novellas]
National Endowment for the Arts Fellowship for fiction
1983 Maxwell Perkins Award, PEN
1983 -1989 Cofounder and editor of Black Lizard Books, publishers of noir fiction
1984 Saroyan: A Biography, with Lawrence Lee An Unfortunate Woman [novel]
1985 PEN Syndicated Fiction Award
1987 Giotto's Circle [poetry]
1988 The Devil Thumbs a Ride and Other Unforgettable Films [essays] American Library Association
Notable Book Award A Day at the Races: The Education of a Race Tracker [memoir/ nonfiction]
1989 Ghosts No Horse Can Carry: Collected Poems 1967-1987
1990 Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula [novel]
Consultant to the film adaptation of Wild At Heart by David Lynch
1991 New Mysteries of Paris [short stories / novellas]
1991, 1996 Sailor's Holiday: The Wild Life of Sailor and Lula [4 Novellas]
1992 Night People [4 Novellas] 59° and Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango [novel]
A Good Man to Know: A Semi-Documentary Fictional Memoir [novel]
1993 Awarded Premio Brancati, Italy "Tricks" and "Blackout" [teleplays]
1994 Arise and Walk [novel]
1995 Baby Cat-Face: A Novel Hotel Room Trilogy [theater]
Perdita Durango [Graphic Novels]
1997 Lost Highway, with David Lynch [screenplay]
Flaubert at Key West [poetry]
The Phantom Father [memoir/nonfiction]
1998 The Sinaloa Story [novel]
Conditions Governing Access
Access is unrestricted to the processed segment (25 linear feet) of the collection. An additional 16 linear feet purchased in 2002, 13 linear feet purchased in 2005, and 3 linear feet purchased in 2016 are closed until processing is complete. One record storage box, currently on deposit, is also been restricted.
Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased, 1997, 2002, 2005, and 2016. Accessions Mss 1997-162, 1998-251, 2000-096, 2002-072, 2002-176, 2004-032, 2004-137, 2005-061, 2005-205, 2005-309, 2013-024, 2016-017.
Authors, American -- 20th century.; Gifford, Barry, 1946-
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - a. Incoming
    - Berg, A. Scott, 1980 Feb 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      1 ANS
    - Blaine, Nell, 1979 Mar 16-1988 Jan 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      2 ANS
    - Bloom, Claire, 1981 Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
      1 ALS
    - Bowles, Paul, 1983 Nov 16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      1 TLS
    - Bromige, David, 1988 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brown, Larry, 1990 Aug 12-1995 Sep 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      9 TLS; 2 postcards
    - Cassidy, Carolyn, 1976-1995 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      2 TLS
    - Chatham, Russell, 1992 Oct 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1993 Jan 11 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Codrescu, Andrei, 1979 Sep 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Corman, Cid, 1985 Feb 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      1 postcard
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1977 Dec 20-1981 Jul 21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Crisp, Quentin, 1980 Apr 12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ford, Richard, 1990 Aug 10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Gold, Herbert, 1980 Jan 28 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hannah, Barry, 1991 Jul 8-1992 Feb 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      2 ALS
    - Harrison, Jim, 1981 Feb 19-1996 Feb 28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      11 TLS, 8 ALS
    - Hass, Robert, 1980 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kazantzakis, Helen, 1983 Mar 22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Leonard, Elmore, 1985 Nov 7-1996 Aug 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      7 TLS, 3 ALS, 1 ANS, TMs, 2 pp. from "Rum Punch"
    - Luján, Rosa Elena [Mrs. B. Travern], 1976 Apr 28 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Mc Carthy, Mary, 1982 Sep 25 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Mc Guane, Tom, 1992 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Metcalf, Paul, 1976 July 8 -19 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      2 TLS; TMs, 2 pp. review of "The Portable Curtis"
    - O'Brien, Geoffrey, 1984 Aug 31 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Palmer, Michael, 1981 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Patchett, Ann, 1995 Jan 24 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Phillips, Jayne Anne, 1994 Nov 22 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      1 TLS (fax)
    - Raymond [?], 1979 Nov 20-24 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      1 ALS; 1 postcard
    - Rossellini, Isabella, 1991 Sep 27 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Snyder, Gary, 1976 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Styron, William, 1985 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Talese, Gay, 1990 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Theroux, Paul, 19-Nov-13 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Thompson, Gifford, 1995 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Van Sant, Gus, 1996 Mar 8 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Wilson, Edmund, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Williams, C. K., 1996 Aug 17 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Yglesias, John [?], 1994 Dec 3 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Young, Al, 1973 July 11 -1982 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      5 ALS
    - Clark City Press, 1991 Oct-Nov (Box 48, Folder 1)
      3 TLS (fax) includes galley proof
  - b. Outgoing
    - Clements, Marshall, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      2 ALS; 3 TLS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1971 Jan 14-May 23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      5 ALS; 5 TLS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1971 May 26-Aug 4 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      6 ALS; 3 TLS; 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1971 Aug 16-25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      3 ALS; 3 TLS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1971 Sep 3-Oct 8 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      5 ALS; 2 TLS; 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1971 Oct 14-Dec 31 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      1 ALS; 1postcard; 1 Doc.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 Jan 8-28 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      4 ALS; 1 TLS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 Feb 5-Mar 19 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      5 ALS; 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 Mar 30-Apr 20 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      4 ALS; 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 Apr 26 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      1 ALS; "Part Two," TMs, 32 pp.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 May 6 -25 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      4 ALS; 1 postcard [includes "Waiting in a cafe" AMs]
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 June 22 -July 19 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 Jul 26-Oct 18 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      7 ALS; 3 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 Oct 31-Nov 28 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      4 ALS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1972 Dec 21 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1973 Jan 9-Aug 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      3 ALS; 10 postcards; 1 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1973 Aug 20-Sep 17 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      1 ALS; 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1973 Oct 2 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      1 ANS; "The last lunchcard Christmas," TMs, 3 pp.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1973 Oct 29-Nov 23 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      4 ALS; 1 ANS; 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1973 Dec 10 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      1 ALS; "Reading for the Greek Resistance," TMs, 3 pp.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1973 Dec 19 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1974 Jan 24-Feb 27 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      2 ALS; 1 ANS; 2 postcards; Clellou, John Holmes. "Introduction: Carolyn Cassady's 'Heart Beat,'" TMs, 3 pp.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1974 Mar 7-May 10 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      3 ALS; 3 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1974 May 18-Dec 24 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      1 ALS; 1 TLS; 5 postcards; "The pearl of San Lucas," TMs, 2 pp.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1975 Jan 28-Mar 11 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      5 ALS; 1 postcard; 1 ANS; 1 photographic col.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1975 Mar 24 -Oct 27 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      6 ALS; 4 postcards; "ASA," TMs, 1 p.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1976 Jan 12-May 19 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 ANS, 7 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1976 May 25-Nov 19 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      2 TLS, 1 ANS, 5 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1977 Jan 25 -June 27 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      5 ALS, 1 ANS, 2 photographs: col.
    - Clements, Marshall, 1977 Jul 8-Nov 28 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 2 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1978 Jan 5-Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      5 postcards, 2 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1978 Sep 19-Oct 27 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      3 ALS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1979 Jan 9-Mar 19 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      2 ALS, 2 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1979 Apr 16-Sep 27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      2 ALS, 2 TLS, 4 ANS, 3 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1979 Oct 1-Dec 28 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      3 ALS, 2 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1980 Jan 12-Mar 12 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      3 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1980 Mar 17-Jun 24 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      6 ANS, 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1980 Jul 7-Aug 19 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      1 TLS, 2 ANS, 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1980 Sep 13-Nov 12 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      1 TLS, 1 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1981 Jan 5-Feb 2 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      1 TLS, 1 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1981 Feb 10-Apr 27 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      2 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 ANS, 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1981 May 4 -July 23 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      3 ALS, 1 ANS, 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1981 Aug 14-Sep 26 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      1 postcard, 2 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1981 Oct 31-Nov 30 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      3 ALS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1982 Jan 7-Mar 12 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      1 ALS, 2 postcard, 4 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1982 Mar 15-May 24 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      1 ALS, 4 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1982 Jun 1-Aug 9 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      3 ALS, 3 ANS, 3 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1982 Aug 16-Dec 13 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      1 ALS, 3 ANS, 2 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1983 Jan 26-Apr 11 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 ANS, 1 postcard, 1 TMs ["A Good Man to Know," 3 pp.]
    - Clements, Marshall, 1983 Apr 15-Apr 22 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      1 ALS, 2 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1983 May 5-Aug 23 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      4 ANS, 4 postcards, 2 photographs: 1 col., 1 b & w
    - Clements, Marshall, 1983 Sept 9 -Oct 18 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 3 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1984 Jan 3-Apr 10 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      3 ALS, 3 ANS, 1 TLS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1984 May 22-Aug 23 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      3 ALS, 4 ANS, 1 AN, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1984 Aug 24-Oct 31 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      2 ALS, 1 TLS, 2 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1984 Nov 27-Dec 17 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      1 ALS, 2 ANS, 1 photograph: color
    - Clements, Marshall, 1985 Jan 10 -Mar 21 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      1 ALS, 2 TLS, 4 ANS, 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1985 Jun 5-Aug 5 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      2 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1985 Aug 13-Sep 11 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1985 Sep 17-Oct 28 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 2 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, 1986 Jan 16-May 22 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      2 TLS, 1 ANS, 2 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1986 May 28-Aug 8 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      2 ALS, 2 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1986 Aug 26-Sep 24 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 AN
    - Clements, Marshall, 1987 Feb 4 -July 6 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      1 TLS, 4 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1987 Aug 10 -Nov 11 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1988 Jan 26-Jun 27 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      1 ALS, 2 ANS, 1 Postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1988 Jun 29-Aug 15 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      1 ALS, 1 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1988 Sep 20 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      1 ALS, 1 TMS ["Port Tropique (French trans.0," 15 pp.]
    - Clements, Marshall, 1988 Oct 3-Dec 12 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1989 Mar 22 -Dec 30 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      1 TLS, 2 ALS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1990 Jan 23-May 9 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 3 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1990 June 18 -July 30 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      1 ALS, 2 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1990 Oct 4-Dec 18 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      1 TLS, 2 ANS, 1 photograph: col
    - Clements, Marshall, 1991 Apr 21-Dec 17 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 ANS, 2 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1992 May 25-Oct 15 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      1 TLS, 2 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1992 Nov 17-Dec 26 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      1 ANS, 2 ALS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1993 Jan 15-Jul 6 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Clements, Marshall, 1993 Jul 27-Dec 22 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      1 ALS, 1 TLS, 1 postcard, 1 ANS
    - Clements, Marshall, 1994 Feb 17-Dec 17 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      1 TLS, 2 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1995 Jan 25-Nov 24 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      2 ALS, 3 ANS, 1 postcard
    - Clements, Marshall, 1996 Mar 6-Dec 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      1 ALS, 3 ANS, 3 postcards
    - Clements, Marshall, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
      10 ANS
    - Wilsted, Thomas, 1996, Sep 3 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Manuscripts
  - 59º & Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango [1 of 6], undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    TMs, 50 pp.
  - 59º & Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango [2 of 6], undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 59º & Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango [3 of 6], undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 59º & Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango [4 of 6], undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    TMs, 29 pp.
  - 59º & Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    AMs 50 pp.
  - 59º & Raining: The Story of Perdita Durango [6 of 6], undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    AMs 65 pp.
  - Arise and Walk: Original Manuscript [front matter] [1 of 7], undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    TMs, 8 pp.; 1 TLs
  - Arise and Walk [2 of 7], undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    TMs, pp. 1-50
  - Arise and Walk [3 of 7], undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    TMs, pp. 51-100
  - Arise and Walk [4 of 7], undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    TMs, pp. 101-150
  - Arise and Walk [5 of 7], undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    TMs, pp. 151-161
  - Arise and Walk [6 of 7], undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    AMs, 52 pp.
  - Arise and Walk [7 of 7], undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    AMs, 74 pp.
  - Arise and Walk [1 of 4], undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    TMs, pp. i-vi, 1-50
  - Arise and Walk [2 of 4], undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Arise and Walk [3 of 4], undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Arise and Walk [4 of 4], undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Arise and Walk: Publicity, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Arise and Walk: Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Baby Cat Face [1 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    TMs, pp. 1-xi, 1-34
  - Baby Cat Face [2 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    TMs, pp. 35-67
  - Baby Cat Face [3 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    TMs, pp. 68-107
  - Baby Cat Face [4 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    TMs, pp. 108-154
  - Baby Cat Face [1 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    ANs, TMsS, pp. 1-39
  - Baby Cat Face [2 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    TMsS pp. 32-80
  - Baby Cat Face [3 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    TMsS pp. 81-120
  - Baby Cat Face [4 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    TMsS pp. 121-154
  - Baby Cat Face [1 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    TMs, pp. i-xiv, 1-40
  - Baby Cat Face [2 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    TMs, pp. 41-90
  - Baby Cat Face [3 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    TMs, pp. 91-140
  - Baby Cat Face [4 of 4], undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    TMs, pp. 141-169
  - Baby Cat Face [1 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    TMs with holographic notes, pp. i-vi, 1-50
  - Baby Cat Face [2 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    TMs with holographic notes, pp. 51-100
  - Baby Cat Face [3 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    TMs with holographic notes, pp. 101-154
  - Baby Cat Face: Editor's Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Baby Cat Face [1 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    TMsS, 57 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [2 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    TMsS, 54 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [3 of 3], undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    TMsS, 63 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [1 of 6], undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    TMs, 25 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [2 of 6], undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Baby Cat Face [3 of 6], undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Baby Cat Face [4 of 6], undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    TMs, 27 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [5 of 6], undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Baby Cat Face [6 of 6], undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    TMs, 34 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [1 of 5], undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    AMs, 26 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [2 of 5], undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Baby Cat Face [3 of 5], undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    AMs, 25 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [4 of 5], undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    AMs, 20 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face [5 of 5], undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    AMs, 17 pp.
  - Baby Cat Face: Rifacimento, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The Back to School (Blacks and) Blues, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    AMs, 4 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [1 of 10], 1991 Feb 14 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    AMs, 18 pp., TMs, 6 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [2 of 10], 1991 Feb 14 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    AMs, 21 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [3 of 10], 1991 Feb 14 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    AMs, 19 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [4 of 10], 1991 Feb 14 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    AMs, 7 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [5 of 10], undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    TMs, 19 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [6 of 10], undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [7of 10], undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
    TMs, 21 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [8of 10], undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    TMs, 20 pp.
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Original Manuscript & Typescript [9 of 10], undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Bad Day for the Leopard Man: Book Six of the Sailor & Lula Novels; Research Materials [10 of 10], undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Bay Area Boxing: It May Be Down But Not Out, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    TMs, 17 pp.
  - Bay Area Boxing: It May Be Down But Not Out, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    TMs, 9 pp.
  - Bay Area Boxing: It May Be Down But Not Out: Proposal Letter with Writing Sample ["Knowing the Ropes"], undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    1 TL, 1 TLS, 2 TMs
  - Beautiful Phantoms: Poems 1968-1978 [1 of 3], undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Beautiful Phantoms: Poems 1968-1978 [2 of 3], undated (Box 9, Folder 28)